PROFILE

Widely accomplished System Administrator with ability to install, maintenance, deploy various hardware and software solutions starting with wide variety of operating systems and different applications. With over 8 years of experience, excellent skills for signal processing and analysis of data packets, with strong ability for network analysis, architecting, deployment, optimization and maintenance. Excellent motivational and educational skills, good team player appropriated with endurance towards given tasks.

SKILLS & EXPERIENCE

Build Automated Machines Images	Packer – Build Automated Machine Images o Embraces modern configuration management by encouraging you to use automated scripts to install and configure the software within your Packer-made images. Packer brings machine images into the modern age, unlocking untapped potential and opening new opportunities to the cloud.
Source Code Management	GitHub – Development platform Bitbucket – Distributed version control system
Cloud Provisioning	Heroku – Managed container system
Platforms	Docker – Software container platform
	Manage apps side-by-side in isolated containers to get better compute density
Cloud CI/CD	TeamCity - Continuous Integration platform
(Continuous Integration and Deployment)	CI platform which enables build very sophisticated automated build pipelines
Business Intelligence Software	Business Intelligence Servers – installation under different OS platforms state-of-health monitoring
	o TIBCO Jasper BI
Caiamala ai ad Cattanana	TIBCO Jasper BI Buildomatic
Seismological Software Installation Deployment	Seismological Data acquisition servers:
and Maintenance	SEISComp v.2.0 – SEISComp v.3.0 (Seattle and Jakarta releases)
	SeedLink server - real-time data acquisition. A rel integration respired access to archive data.
	 ArcLink server - rapid access to archive data Seismic Handler server/client - waveform signal processing data
Seismological Software	Seismic Handler server/client – waveform signal processing data Seismological Data manipulation processing and Event visualization, mapping, quality control, state-of-health monitoring:
and Hardware Signal	GEODAS - re-picking, waveform visualization
Processing and	Seismic Analysis Code – SAC
Conversion	Receiver Function Analysis – RFTN CODES
	MATLAB 2013a and modules:
	 FuncLAB – Interactive toolbox for handling receiver function datasets
	 Moment Tensor Inversion – ISOLA (GUI for moment Tensor Retrieval)
	 M-Map – mapping utility
	 Coulomb 3 – utility for earthquake nodal planes
	○ Wolfram Research Mathematica software solution starting from v.5 – v.10 mainly for physics equations solving problems
Cloud and Virtualization	VMware software solutions:
software design, installation, deployment	○ ESXI servers (v.3.0 – v.5.5 update 2) with VMware Tools for Linux and Windows Guests
and maintenance	VMware vSphere and Operations:
	vCenter (Linux-virtual appliance and Windows implementation)
	• vCenter Server Heartbeat
	• vCenter Operation Manager
	• vSphere Client
	vSphere Management Assistant (vMA)vShield Manager
	vSphere Data Protection
	Certificate Automation Tool
	VMware Workstation v.7-v.11 with VMware Player
	 VMware Fusion
	 VMware Converter
	Oracle VM software solutions:
	Oracle VM Virtual Box
	Amazon Web Services (AWS):
	 Amazon Elastic Computer Cloud (EC2)
	 Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)
	 Amazon low-cost storage Service (Glacier)
	 Amazon global distribute content (CloudFront)
	 Amazon secure integration on-premises IT environments with cloud storage (Storage Gateway)

	 Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS)
	 Amazon scalable NoSQL data storage (DynamoDB)
	 Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)
	 Amazon scalable and highly available Domain Name System (Route 53)
	 Amazon Identity and Access Management (IAM)
	 Amazon Monitoring for Resources and applications (CloudWatch)
	 Amazon Simple Email Service (SES)
	Open VZ, XEN and KVM solutions:
	Core Open VZ containers
	 XEN – open source virtualization
	 KVM – virtualization
	Open source Cloud Solutions
	Synology Cloud v3.5-6.2
	 Ubuntu Open Stack Juno
Backup software	o Acronis Backup and Recovery Server v.11-v15
solutions, performing, restoration, safe	o Acronis True Image 2014
extraction of data	o CloneZilla
	o M3 Bitlocker Recovery
	o O&O Diskimage Professional 8
	o Paragon Backup and Recovery
	o EaseUS To Do Backup solution suite
	o HDD Regenerator
	 Heiren's Boot CD – many various software solutions
	o Veeam Backup Management Suite v7.0 including (Veeam One Business View, Veeam One Monitor, Veeam One Reporter)
Installation, deployment,	o Linux distributions (Debian, Ubuntu, CentOS, Suse, Linux Mint, etc.)
maintenance of Operating Systems	o Microsoft Windows Home, Professional and Server versions
	o Raspberry Pi OS systems
Installation, deployment,	Web servers including automation embedded web services scripts:
optimization and backup of Application Servers,	• Apache2
CMS platform, Control	■ Nginx
Panel Platforms,	• IIS
Collaboration platforms	 LAMPP, XAMPP, WAMP
	Mail servers:
	 Dovecot, Courier, Postfix, Mercury
	DNS servers:
	 MyDNS, Bind, PowerDNS, MS SQL
	Database servers:
	 MySQL, MS SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
	VOIP servers:
	 Asterisk, Elastix, Trixbox, 3CX
	RTMP servers:
	 Adobe Flash Streaming server v3.0-v5.0 with Flash Media Encoder v3.0-v3.5
	RED 5 Media Server
	 WOWZA Media Streaming Systems – developer edition
	CMS Platforms:
	Joomla, Wordpress, Drupal, Moodle
	Control Panel Platforms:
	• cPanel, phpMyadmin
	Collaboration platforms:
Installation	 Zimbra – open source messaging and Collaboration system
Installation, modification,	NAS systems:
deployment,	 FreeNAS
maintenance of NAS	• OpenFiler
systems, WAN Load	WAN Load Balancers
Balancers, VPN systems,	 ZeroShell
Servers Monitoring	• PEN
	VPN systems:
	 Microsoft VPN servers (2003, 2008, 2012)
	Open-VPN
	 SoftEther VPN server
	Server and Network Monitoring:

TECHNOLOGY PROFILE

	 PagerDuty
	■ RRD Cacti
	 Paessler – RTPG monitoring
	 Boundary
	 New Relic
	 Nagios
	 SUMOLogic
Architecture, installation,	Network Architecture, installation, testing, optimization and security with ability for problem solving on-premises and
deployment, maintenance of hardware	using software solutions.
network	Testing, Optimization and Penetration of WAN/LAN networks
implementations, testing,	BackTrack system network tools and scripts
optimization of network stability and security	KALI system penetration tools and scripts

WORK EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

FEBRUARY 2015 – CURRENTLY – ITGMA (CLOUD SUPPORT ENGINEER)

NOVEMBER 2012 – FEBRUARY 2015 – SEISMOLOGICAL OBSERVATORY OF REPUBLIC MACEDONIA (SYSTEM NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR – TELEMETRIC NETWORKS)

SEPTEMBER 2008 – NOVEMBER 2012 – FACULTY OF NATURAL SCIENCES AND MATHEMATICS – SKOPJE (SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR)

POSITION RESPONSIBILITIES AS:

SEISMOLOGICAL OBSERVATORY OF REPUBLIC MACEDONIA: SYSTEM NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR - TELEMETRIC NETWORKS

- O DEPLOYING AND MAINTAINING OF NETWORK AND SERVERS AT THE SEISMOLOGICAL OBSERVATORY OF R. MACEDONIA (SORM), USING NEW VIRTUALIZATION TECHNOLOGY (VMWARE PRODUCTS).
- O INSURING FLAWLESS DATA ACQUISITION FROM ALL BASE STATION (REMOTELY AND ON-SITE) IN THE TERRITORY OF R.MACEDONIA EQUIPPED WITH KINEMETRICS QUANTERA 330S AND QUANTERA HRS DATA DIGITIZERS.

 ARCHIVING OF ALL SIGNALS AND PREPARING FOR FURTHER ANALYSIS WITH DIFFERENT (PREVIOUSLY MENTIONED SOFTWARE AND ADEQUATE MODULES)
- O CALIBRATION, TESTING AND DEPLOYMENT OF KINEMETRICS QUANTERA SYSTEMS WITH EPS-EARTHOUAKE SENSORS, WAVE 24 DIGITIZERS WITH WIDE RANGE RANGER 1 AND RANGER 2 SENSORS.

FACULTY OF NATURAL SCIENCES AND MATHEMATICS – SKOPJE: SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

- O CONDUCTING ON-SITE NECESSARY HARDWARE AND SOFTWARE INTERVENTIONS AT EVERY COMPUTER LABORATORY
- O DATA ENTRY INTO IKNOW STUDENT SERVICE SYSTEM
- O VARIOUS HARDWARE DIAGNOSIS AND REPAIR, SOFTWARE INSTALLATION AND MAINTENANCE FOR STUDENT SERVICES AND FACULTY MANAGEMENT.
- O INSTALLATION, MANAGEMENT AND MAINTENANCE OF ALL WEB, MAIL, DNS, DATABASE SERVERS AT FACULTY.
- O CONSULTATIONS ABOUT CREATING TENDER DOCUMENTATION FOR SPECIFIC HARDWARE AND SOFTWARE SYSTEMS.
- MAINTENANCE OF THE OFFICIAL WEB SITE OF FACULTY AND ITS MODULES AND ADDITIONAL CMS PLATFORMS AND DIFFERENT PLUGINS.
- o Planning, modification and maintenance of several web services for various needs of different institutes (<u>www.prirodninauki.com</u> currently not active; <u>www.blumovataksonomija.com</u> currently not active; <u>www.fizika.pmf.ukim.mk</u> –active; <u>www.nacestojanov.net</u> active)
- ACTIVE PARTICIPATION AS A LECTURER IN THE OFFICIAL TWO YEAR EDUBUNTU PROGRAM THAT WAS CONDUCTED AT ALL TERRITORY OF R. MACEDONIA
- O PLANNING, DEVELOPING, MAINTENANCE OF THE OFFICIAL WEB PORTAL www.edubuntu.info (which was active 3 years, it was meant to help of all 2000 participants high and primary school teachers, in one place to acknowledge all necessary basic information for working with new Linux operating system Edubuntu, and their specific set of programs in order to strengthen and develop new skills in their primary and high school students, and to fully integrate with Government programs for intensive every-day use of computer for every student).

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS:

- o Business analysis, entrepreneur activities regarding project www.opfolio.com Financial Portfolio Risk management web-based service/software
- INSTALLATION, AND MAINTENANCE OF DIGITAL ARCHIVE OF INSTITUTE OF ETHNOLOGY <u>www.archiveiea.net</u>
- o Real-time live streaming of European Junior Wrestling Championship 02-07.07.2013, Skopje, R. Macedonia www.wrestlingskopje2013.com —currently not active. (Adobe FMS 5.0)
- o Real-time live broadcast of scientific paper from PhD. Oliver Zajkov at International Conference for Physicists Puebla Mexico 24-27 May 2012. (adobe FMS 3.0)
- o Real-time live streaming of IX and X International Conferences of Physicists via www.dfrm.org
- O DESIGN, MODIFICATION, IMPLEMENTATION AND WEB HOSTING OF THE FOLLOWING CMS PROJECTS:
 - WWW.DFRM.ORG
 - WWW.IZLEZ.MK
 - WWW.FEHMILAB.NET
 - WWW.IZLEZ.MK
 - WWW.PUMPERSMUSIC.COM
 - WWW.LOGOSPLUS.EU
 - WWW.SKPRENTAL.COM
 - WWW.MACEDONIA-CAR-RENTAL.COM
 - <u>WWW.ASTRONOMIJA-MKD.COM;</u>
 - WWW.MACEDONIACARRENT.COM
 - WWW.MERKEZJUPA.GOV.MK
 - WWW.HIDROLOGIJA.COM CURRENTLY NOT ACTIVE
 - <u>WWW.KANEO-DIVING.COM</u> CURRENTLY NOT ACTIVE
 - WWW.MARKER.MK
 - WWW.MULTI-DEKOR.COM
 - <u>www.shutters4less.com.au</u>

EDUCATION

University: Physics student (11 exams till graduation) – Faculty of Natural Sciences and Mathematics – Physics Institute, University "St. Cyril and Methodius" Skopje, Macedonia

COURSES, TRAININGS, SEMINARS, WEBINARS, CERTIFICATES

Certificates:

- o AWS Certified SysOps Administrator Associate (December 2019)
- o SUMOLogic Security Analytics (August 2019)
- AWS Certified Solution Architect Associate (July 2018)
- New Relic Certified Performance Pro (February 2018)
- o SUMOLogic Power Admin (February 2018)
- AWS Certified Developer Associate (July 2017)
- o SUMOLogic Pro User (August 2017)
- SUMOLogic –Power User (August 2017)

Accreditations:

TECHNOLOGY PROFILE

- AWS Business Accreditation (February 2015)
- AWS Technical Accreditation (February 2015)

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- English Language Driving Licence: B category